<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Engin Doğusoy</title>
		<link>https://engd.github.io/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Engin Doğusoy</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://engd.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>AWS EC2: Self-referencing Security Groups</title>
			<link>https://engd.github.io/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://engd.github.io/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
			<description>Problem This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
Investigation DRY is a good design goal and Hugo does a great job supporting it.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h3 id="problem">Problem</h3>

<p>This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.</p>

<h3 id="investigation">Investigation</h3>

<p>DRY is a good design goal and Hugo does a great job supporting it. Part of the art of a good template is knowing when to add a new template and when to update an existing one. While you&rsquo;re figuring that out, accept that you&rsquo;ll be doing some refactoring. Hugo makes that easy and fast, so it&rsquo;s okay to delay splitting up a template.</p>

<h3 id="solution">Solution</h3>

<p>DRY is a good design goal and Hugo does a great job supporting it. Part of the art of a good template is knowing when to add a new template and when to update an existing one. While you&rsquo;re figuring that out, accept that you&rsquo;ll be doing some refactoring. Hugo makes that easy and fast, so it&rsquo;s okay to delay splitting up a template.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
